[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c63c", "question": "What number is indicated by the Roman Numeral \"D\"?", "answer": "500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3c", "question": "During what decade did the Charleston become the dance craze?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec7", "question": "The album \"American Beauty/American Psycho\" was released in 2015 by which American rock band?", "answer": "Fall Out Boy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391fb", "question": "Who played Vincent Vega in \"Pulp Fiction\"?", "answer": "John Travolta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ed43eccd244b1771b64500f", "question": "When a horse gallops its hooves act as almost four additional what? ", "answer": "Hearts", "category": "Science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a10", "question": "What does the sailor hold in his right hand on Margaret Thatcher's coat of arms?", "answer": "Binoculars", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb29d5c9bff04efae6d75a", "question": "Who wrote the novels \"The Joy Luck Club\" and \"The Kitchen God's Wife\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a908", "question": "What major river runs through Boston?", "answer": "Charles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf49", "question": "What is the next-to-last event?", "answer": "Penultimate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3312ff048f679a45aaeb", "question": "What is the loudest animal on Earth?", "answer": "Sperm whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133972b", "question": "How old was Michael Jackson when he died?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60077f15bd51d85e222ab63b", "question": "In biology, a relationship between individuals of two species in which one species obtains food or other benefits from the other without either harming or benefiting the latter is called what?", "answer": "Commensalism", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600243894be4723ccac22198", "question": "What was the name of the first book in Laura Ingalls Wilder\u2019s \"Little House\" series?", "answer": "\"Little House in the Big Woods\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f356ff048f679a45aabf", "question": "What are the lakes of Titan made of?", "answer": "Methane", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b622", "question": "What does MW stand for on a radio?", "answer": "Medium wave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d19", "question": "In what country was composer Ludwig van Beethoven born?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d47103f8e329de4f877897", "question": "What is the brewery featured in the British soap opera \"Coronation Street\"?", "answer": "Newton and Ridley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c7c8877e98cb977789d7", "question": "Which Mediterranean city has an area nicknamed \"The White City\"?", "answer": "Tel Aviv", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb66", "question": "What delivery company was founded in 1969 by Adrian Dalsey, Larry Hillblom, and Robert Lynn?", "answer": "DHL", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdff0eb668d7dfe168b5b3", "question": "In which country is the alcoholic drink Pulque consumed?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600b88d91d8c1817608d53f8", "question": "Originally called pimento, what popular spice was first grown in Jamaica?", "answer": "Allspice -- It is a fruit from a tropical evergreen tree, that is dried and either sold as berries or ground up to make the spice.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdd5d260499cffc60b84231", "question": "A 1634 Spanish decree called what city \"Key to the New World and Rampart of the West Indies\"?", "answer": "Havana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e963a7ccba3ffe45786ea", "question": "Poona was the original name of what sport?", "answer": "Badminton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff2566b31a458464a93c460", "question": "What is traditional bubble gum made of?", "answer": "Chicle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a484", "question": "What is the name of the warm dry wind which blows over the Rocky Mountains?", "answer": "The Chinook", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afea", "question": "The Battle of Bull Run occurred during what war?", "answer": "Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d10", "question": "What nationality was author Jules Verne?", "answer": "French", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af56", "question": "What was the great discovery made in 1922 by Howard Carter and Lord Caernarvon?", "answer": "The Tomb of Tutankhamun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a25f2616682715b82711cea", "question": "Which Canadian city is know as \"Steeltown\"?", "answer": "Hamilton, Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a12a", "question": "Which film did Duran Duran take their name from?", "answer": "Barbarella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70c", "question": "Chicago is located on the shore of what lake?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58be2d7d8faf425cf37add7f", "question": "The game \"Cities: Skylines\" was developed by which Finnish video game company?", "answer": "Colossal Order", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede0b96ce05a3942286dba", "question": "Which Bavarian castle did Walt Disney sculpt Cinderella's after?", "answer": "Neuschwanstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d0778e870e6f05ba600865", "question": "What is the capital city of Iran?", "answer": "Tehran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e21", "question": "What movie is loosely based on Philip K. Dick's novel \"Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep\"?", "answer": "Blade Runner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b48e649076251badbeaa8", "question": "Who was the first American woman in space?", "answer": "Sally Ride -- One of six women selected for NASA Astronaut Group 8, she traveled on Space Shuttle Challenger's STS-7 mission.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cdc8bb53d1af658864ec", "question": "What year marked the first appearance of Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "1939", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b454", "question": "Where did Abraham Lincoln give his historic speech?", "answer": "Gettysburg, Pennsylvania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a406", "question": "Where in Canada would you find Mount Queen Elizabeth?", "answer": "Banff National Park", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6fb", "question": "The Saffir Simpson scale is a scale which classifies the intensities of what?", "answer": "Hurricanes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69afd20565ad31a57c759", "question": "What country sent troops in the form of \"Division Azul\" to assist Germany in its fight with the Soviet Union during World War II?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb47", "question": "Within 3 years, either way, in what year did Lou Gehrig deliver his famous farewell speech at Yankee Stadium?", "answer": "1939", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be41", "question": "What Hyundai model gets its name from the Spanish word for \"shark\"?", "answer": "The Tiburon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d5b", "question": "What year saw the start of the \"Twilight\" book series?", "answer": "2005", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a1", "question": "Who played the role of Michael Clayton in the 2007 movie by the same name?", "answer": "George Clooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f4a", "question": "What Latin phrase actually comes from a poem, attributed to Virgil, about a salad recipe?", "answer": "E Pluribus Unum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339229", "question": "Who is pictured with her eyes wide open on posters for Kubrick's \"Eyes Wide Shut\" movie?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c45", "question": "Who composed the score for the musical \"Kiss Me Kate\"?", "answer": "Cole Porter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b978", "question": "What is the name of the cup used by Christ at the last supper?", "answer": "The Holy Grail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e0", "question": "Which Captain & Tennille hit was written by Neil Sedaka?", "answer": "Love Will Keep Us Together", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b34", "question": "What woodwind instrument is sometimes called a \"licorice stick\"?", "answer": "Clarinet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7df", "question": "What are the bumps on the tongue that carry the taste buds called?", "answer": "Papillae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d0e12596a59cbdfbd382", "question": "Which country was the first to enact daylight savings time?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f6", "question": "What 1970's TV show spawned the catchphrase \"Up your nose with a rubber hose\"?", "answer": "Welcome Back, Kotter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fca", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional band \"Jesse and the Rippers\"?", "answer": "Full House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a662", "question": "What region was explored by Vitus Bering?", "answer": "Arctic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c62b8ab0ae4aacefc17eee2", "question": "Metallica released what song on the album \"Mission: Impossible 2\"?", "answer": "I Disappear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0d6ff048f679a45aaa8", "question": "Trypanophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Needles or injections", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133903a", "question": "Under what pen name did Hector Hugh Munro write?", "answer": "Saki", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c3e99a0ebfabb9c85d8a974", "question": "Whose first wife was actress Jane Wyman?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2f", "question": "Which two actresses on TV's \"Charlie's Angels\" were meant to be portraying sisters?", "answer": "Farrah Fawcett-Majors and Cheryl Ladd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c571fbde8045e48466ac", "question": "What is the universal solvent?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefc1e46ce05a3942286f17", "question": "Who originally recorded the song \"Blue Bayou\"?", "answer": "Roy Orbison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f3", "question": "Which pass connects Afghanistan to Pakistan?", "answer": "The Khyber Pass", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594d05eb1a1c922dd1ac64a6", "question": "Switzerland and what other country both have square flags?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c18", "question": "Who created the TV show \"SpongeBob SquarePants\"?", "answer": "Stephen Hillenburg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbe", "question": "Which war was fought along the 38th parallel?", "answer": "The Korean War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b498e662d71a53650fec", "question": "Which author wrote the \"Winnie-the-Pooh\" books?", "answer": "A. A. Milne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b1", "question": "What describes the amount of light allowed to pass through a camera lens?", "answer": "Aperture", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa3f57c73aa70ea0b70afe", "question": "Which U.S. state has the unofficial motto \"May The 14th Star Shine Bright\"?", "answer": "Vermont (The unofficial motto \u201cStella Quarta Decima Fulgeat\u201d was adopted in 2015 after being proposed by a Vermonter Latin student.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523e3f736d4be723796b4d", "question": "Which region of Canada would you find Canada\u2019s Technology Triangle?", "answer": "Waterloo Region", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c1a", "question": "What fictional town is the TV show \"SpongeBob SquarePants\" set in?", "answer": "Bikini Bottom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9e3", "question": "What does an anemometer measure?", "answer": "Wind speed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c8", "question": "In what year was Harvard University founded?", "answer": "1636", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb0f17e83c707845b210a", "question": "What is the technical name for having different-colored eyes?", "answer": "Heterchromia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde6", "question": "What floor number is often skipped in Chinese buildings, as the thirteenth is in the West?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8f", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Robert Diggs?", "answer": "RZA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c3", "question": "What US state is represented by the figures of Andrew Jackson and John Sevier in the Capitol's Statuary Hall?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe735d0eec85e375820b252", "question": "Who was the architect of Operation Market Garden?", "answer": "General Bernard Montgomery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a086", "question": "Who is Issur Danielovitch better known as?", "answer": "Kirk Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd3e0ec223966ae8f88c9", "question": "Which superhero does Mark Watney emulate near the end of \"The Martian\"?", "answer": "Iron Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f3", "question": "What year marked the debut of the Volkswagen Golf GTI?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acca", "question": "What city became capital of Cuba in 1519?", "answer": "Havana", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a3", "question": "Who plays Pacey Witter on the TV show \"Dawson's Creek\"?", "answer": "Joshua Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339578", "question": "The movie, \"It's a Wonderful Life\", what did Clarence receive for accomplishing his task?", "answer": "Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339332", "question": "In what year did the TV show \"The Hills\" premier on TV?", "answer": "2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b736", "question": "The original recipe for \"pound cake\" called for a pound of which ingredients?", "answer": "Flour, butter, sugar, eggs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad77", "question": "Who was the first person to fly solo across the Atlantic ocean?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2de", "question": "What year did actor Stan Laurel die?", "answer": "1965", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c56", "question": "When was the book \u201cNational Velvet\u201d first published?", "answer": "1935", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a69", "question": "For what 1997 film did Kim Basinger win a Best Supporting Actress Oscar?", "answer": "L.A. Confidential", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a71a", "question": "What river flows between Nebraska and Iowa?", "answer": "Missouri River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a7b", "question": "What was Bette Midler\u2019s only #1 song on the Billboard Hot 100 singles chart?", "answer": "Wind Beneath My Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef66216ce05a3942286e77", "question": "Who voiced Miss Piggy originally?", "answer": "Frank Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6d", "question": "All members of the \"Jackson 5\" were born in which US city?", "answer": "Gary, Indiana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c0", "question": "Wanamaker's of Philadelphia first US store to install what in 1878?", "answer": "Electric illumination", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e3", "question": "In The Simpsons, what was Maggie's first word?", "answer": "Daddy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f88", "question": "Who is the author of the book \"Spark Joy\"?", "answer": "Marie Kondo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4bd849076251badbeac9", "question": "What country's declaration of war triggered the start of World War I?", "answer": "After Bosnian Serb Gavrilo Princip assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand, Austria-Hungary declared war on Serbia in July 1914.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e3", "question": "Do ants sleep?", "answer": "No", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c963", "question": "Parr, Smolt and Grilse are lifecycle stages for what fish?", "answer": "Salmon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e27", "question": "What began as a ligature of the letters \"e\" and \"t\"?", "answer": "The ampersand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa55bbc73aa70ea0b70b26", "question": "In which Asian city is the historic waterfront called The Bund?", "answer": "Shanghai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff14679b0ee8c595b6d39c0", "question": "What classic book inspired the name of Starbucks?", "answer": "Moby Dick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb17", "question": "In late 2005, on what internet dating site did Dr. Phil begin writing an advice column for?", "answer": "Match.com", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e37", "question": "Who plays drums on the Beatles track \"Back in the U.S.S.R.\"?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c819", "question": "In what part of the body would you find amniotic fluid?", "answer": "The uterus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddf2f6ce05a3942286daf", "question": "Which NBA player once costarred alongside Jean-Claude Van Damme in a major Hollywood action movie?", "answer": "Dennis Rodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99b3e21a8909e5c332d29", "question": "Who played the main female character in the 1939 film \"Destry Rides Again\"?", "answer": "Marlene Dietrich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93d576bd93ce3a4e5f6b4", "question": "What type of rock is formed by consolidation of molten magma?", "answer": "Igneous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b7abc6f6490a8cc1a6e529a", "question": "What does the \"c\" in \"E=mc\u00b2\" represent?", "answer": "The speed of light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd26", "question": "What Bruins and Rangers legend founded the Tampa Bay Lightning in 1991?", "answer": "Phil Esposito", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f0", "question": "Who painted \"The Boy in the Red Vest\"?", "answer": "Paul C\u00e9zanne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b571c2367df192a942e3371", "question": "What is the capital of Togo?", "answer": "Lome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb1", "question": "What are the seven deadly sins?", "answer": "Greed, Envy, Gluttony, Sloth, Lust, Pride And Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899b5d60d398dc9cf7a69c", "question": "Where is the Grand Canal?", "answer": "Venice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fdb", "question": "The family on the TV show \"Married...with Children\" was named in honor of what wrestler?", "answer": "KIng Kong Bundy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc49", "question": "What nickname did tennis player Pete Sampras go by during his career?", "answer": "Pistol Pete", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b712", "question": "Which New York newspaper wrote \"yes Virginia, there is a Santa Claus\"?", "answer": "The New York Sun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b497649076251badbeaae", "question": "Where in the world was Richard Nixon when he delivered his infamous \"I am not a crook\" speech?", "answer": "Disney World (Orlando, Florida)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed2", "question": "By what name is El-Hajj Malik El-Shabazz better known?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffe4b4347818f5674af01b0", "question": "From which novel is this quote \"My courage always rises with every attempt to intimidate me.\"?", "answer": "\"Pride and Prejudice\" (The protagonist of the novel, Elizabeth, makes this revelation to Mr. Darcy, her counterpart in the novel.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f566a133a95c66dc4fe764", "question": "Germany's World War I allies were Austria-Hungary, Bulgaria, and which empire?", "answer": "Ottoman Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b588", "question": "When was Twitter first launched?", "answer": "2006", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e3f3b35cb9e8bda6821365", "question": "What year was the Rosetta Stone inscribed?", "answer": "196 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5906823cff9c0647b50a809b", "question": "Which NFL team won Super Bowl 50?", "answer": "Denver Broncos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990af23b72eedf883a8c704", "question": "What is Chopin's \"Piano Sonata in B flat minor\" also known as?", "answer": "The Funeral March", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe938516bd93ce3a4e5f683", "question": "Koinoniphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Rooms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9e", "question": "What is the capital of Uzbekistan?", "answer": "Tashkent", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda2", "question": "What last name is shared by Clinton cabinet member Henry and \"The House on Mango Street\" author Sandra?", "answer": "Cisneros", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339724", "question": "What is Elton John's real name?", "answer": "Reginald Dwight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c94d", "question": "What line on a map connects places of equal rainfall?", "answer": "Isohyet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c978", "question": "What mineral is also referred to as \"Fool's gold\"?", "answer": "Pyrite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab84", "question": "What is the second largest state in the US?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e3cd06d333868d34d72f", "question": "Who invented the first steam locomotive?", "answer": "George Stephenson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601370f61381754895396387", "question": "Who said, \"We came, we saw, we kicked its ass\"?", "answer": "Dr. Peter Venkman in the film \"Ghostbusters\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c5c50775fa611bce67cb", "question": "Turmeric is a popular spice that is used in Asian dishes.  What other use does it have?", "answer": "Turmeric is also a powerful anti-inflammatory often used in traditional medicine.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca46", "question": "In the body what may be endocrine or exocrine?", "answer": "Glands", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c096", "question": "In what sport do teams compete for the Swaythling Cup?", "answer": "Table tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d45b2596a59cbdfbd3a2", "question": "What cells are responsible for forming new bone?", "answer": "Osteoblasts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0de59fcbed638185eaa15", "question": "Which U.S. state has the longest width east to west?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7cd6c877e98cb97778a36", "question": "In which U.S. state was Taylor Swift born?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600b88621d8c1817608d53f2", "question": "Choux and filo are types of what?", "answer": "Pastry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a857", "question": "Which building houses the world's biggest four-faced chiming clock?", "answer": "Minneapolis City Hall", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7e", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The Last of the Mohicans\" set?", "answer": "Seven Years' War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d01", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"1984\"?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd73bec223966ae8f88d8", "question": "In Michael Phelps\u2019 last-ever Olympic relay, what stroke did he swim?", "answer": "Butterfly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b760", "question": "Triple Sec is a clear liqueur of what flavor?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b90", "question": "What Kenny Rogers song title is his mother's first name?", "answer": "Lucille", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c416", "question": "How many horns did a triceratops have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae1", "question": "Khartoum is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f164946f9b80650dbe7f929", "question": "What is Harry Potter's middle name?", "answer": "James", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5af46ce05a3942286e0f", "question": "In the film \"One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest,\" what is R. P. McMurphy's first name?", "answer": "Randle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f3", "question": "What range contains the world's highest mountains not located in Asia?", "answer": "The Andes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339796", "question": "Fond of flesh and fava beans, what bad guy was named the American film institutes top villain of all time?", "answer": "Hannibal Lecter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c1540775fa611bce67c2", "question": "Dysmorphia is a mental disorder characterized by what?", "answer": "The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b5", "question": "What was the birth name of sharpshooter Annie Oakley?", "answer": "Phoebe Ann Mosey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bd05cb540191c55fd523fb5", "question": "What video game, that peaked in the late 2000's, got people to try stumping a cartoon genie?", "answer": "Akinator", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d971908b8581f80b092a8", "question": "What country was host to the \u201c2017 World Expo\u201d?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338903", "question": "What Ian Fleming novel's title is the nickname of the character Francisco Scaramanga?", "answer": "The Man with the Golden Gun", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef2", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Quasimodo?", "answer": "The Hunchback of Notre Dame", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d66e2596a59cbdfbd3aa", "question": "What organization unveiled the largest machine on Earth in 2008?", "answer": "CERN", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c1", "question": "Which car manufacturer's name translates from Latin as \"to roll\"?", "answer": "Volvo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b7cfe662d71a53651018", "question": "In which city is the Prado Art Gallery?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3a", "question": "What was World War I known as before World War II?", "answer": "The Great War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58bb3355e368446ca7bd6843", "question": "Who is credited with the invention of the Phillips screw design?", "answer": "John P. Thompson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac1d", "question": "Paramaribo is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Suriname", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22a", "question": "The song \"I'll Be Missing You\" is a tribute to who?", "answer": "The Notorious B.I.G.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3d", "question": "What year did actor Anthony Hopkins become a naturalized citizen of the US?", "answer": "2000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cad", "question": "Who completed his famous bird paintings in 1839?", "answer": "John J. Audubon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fa", "question": "What does ZIP as in ZIP code stand for?", "answer": "Zone Improvement Project", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfed", "question": "Who was America's first billionaire?", "answer": "John D. Rockefeller", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a86a", "question": "Which Bay is located to the north of Spain?", "answer": "Bay of Biscay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c195", "question": "During the 1980s, who replaced Bob Froese as the #1 goaltender for the Philadelphia Flyers?", "answer": "Ron Hextall", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339101", "question": "Which famous composer wrote the opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "Georges Bizet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5eb736465e259d786908732b", "question": "What was the name of the US Navy boat that had the nickname \"Old Ironsides\"?", "answer": "USS Constitution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e9", "question": "Emmental cheese originated in what country?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a422", "question": "What is the capital of New Zealand?", "answer": "Wellington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febaee37e83c707845b20f8", "question": "What year was the first black hole discovered?", "answer": "1971", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba55", "question": "Who coached the Chicago Bulls to their first NBA championship in 1991?", "answer": "Phil Jackson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bd", "question": "What was the name of the nightclub that Peter Gunn frequented?", "answer": "Mothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b812", "question": "What is the nickname of Alcatraz Prison?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e92e47ccba3ffe45786be", "question": "What comic novel did Stella Gibbons publish in 1932?", "answer": "Cold Comfort Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51b7aff04d658268c930e", "question": "What singers lure sailors to crash on the rocks with their songs?", "answer": "Circe warned Odysseus of the Sirens, bird-like women whose beautiful singing caused sailors to crash to their death.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58bb3216e368446ca7bd6840", "question": "Which element has the lowest boiling point?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73602eec85e375820b257", "question": "Abraham Lincoln, Julius Caesar, Tutankhamen and Osama bin Laden all suffered from what disorder?", "answer": "Marfan syndrome", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397dd", "question": "Which Hollywood Actor was born Issur Danielovitch in 1918?", "answer": "Kirk Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd1", "question": "What duo's biggest hits are found on 1985's \"Songs from the Big Chair\" album?", "answer": "Tears for Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c520", "question": "Polaris is commonly known as what star?", "answer": "The North Star", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a543", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Ocean State\"?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389c3", "question": "What kinds of creatures were Flopsy and Mopsy in the first book by Beatrix Potter?", "answer": "Rabbits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa4", "question": "Who was Oscar-nominated for playing a telegraph boy in \"The Human Comedy\"?", "answer": "Mickey Rooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35e", "question": "What was the first country to have a public monorail system?", "answer": "UK", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae1", "question": "In what country was the International Red Cross founded?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa1", "question": "What TV show's cops operate out of a converted church they call \"the Barn\"?", "answer": "The Shield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae85", "question": "In 1800, John Adams became the first US president to live where?", "answer": "In the White House", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b504", "question": "What are A.C. Milan, Ajax and Real Madrid?", "answer": "Soccer clubs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aba", "question": "For what movie did Cher win a Best Actress Oscar?", "answer": "Moonstruck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b120", "question": "What historical figure appeared on the face of the US dollar coins minted from 1979 to 1981, and again in 1999?", "answer": "Susan B. Anthony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fed2bbaec223966ae8f8911", "question": "What is the name of the smelly green ghost in \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Slimer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b3", "question": "In The Simpsons, Bart wins first prize at the science fair by proving what?", "answer": "Hamsters can fly planes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41e", "question": "Who caused the collapse of Barings Bank and inspired the film \"Rogue Trader\"?", "answer": "Nick Leeson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae9485574a5ce6b56b8249", "question": "\"Nobody Does it Better\" was the theme song of which Bond film?", "answer": "The Spy Who Loved Me", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca57", "question": "Christopher Cockerell is best known for invented what?", "answer": "The hovercraft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015eabbfe83fe1f2a824bf3", "question": "What does the color red represent in the American flag?", "answer": "Red symbolizes hardiness and valor.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bfdffe3b668d7dfe168b5bd", "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac00", "question": "What is a native of Tangier called?", "answer": "Tangerian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd9937e83c707845b217b", "question": "What is the name of the woman Mario is attempting to save from the giant ape in the original Donkey Kong?", "answer": "Pauline", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f7a", "question": "What did Aristotle claim as the most delicate of table meats?", "answer": "Camel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339552", "question": "What TV show centered on the exploits of physicist Dr. Sam Beckett?", "answer": "Quantum Leap", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3bd7ff048f679a45ab38", "question": "What is the smallest horse in the world?", "answer": "Fallabella", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea49efff048f679a45abbd", "question": "On which part of the body is an angioplasty performed?", "answer": "Blood vessel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa55b3c73aa70ea0b70b25", "question": "Which Central American country has a name which translates to English as \"The Saviour\"?", "answer": "El Salvador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ad", "question": "Stockholm is located along what sea?", "answer": "The Baltic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c374c815febcc896f926f", "question": "Who wrote the detective novel \"The Maltese Falcon\"?", "answer": "Dashiell Hammett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba141874c93a3298b2124", "question": "Caracas is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133929a", "question": "What video game developer created the hit video game \"Halo\"?", "answer": "Bungie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596dfcfa9616e6c6d4eba4f3", "question": "What year did the video game Grand Theft Auto V come out?", "answer": "2013", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6f75a9e54d890926f6d1", "question": "What was the capital of Michigan before Lansing?", "answer": "Detroit -- Due to Detroit's proximity to Canada, a perceived threat at the time, Lansing became the state's capital in 1847.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b628", "question": "\"St. Vitus's Dance\" is what?", "answer": "A type of brain disorder", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339045", "question": "What artist composed the opera \"Tannhauser\"?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba19", "question": "What football championship was first played in 1967?", "answer": "Super Bowl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e4", "question": "In what country was the \"Michelin Guide\" first published in 1900?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b953", "question": "In a game of basketball, how many players are on the court at one time?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a09b", "question": "What was the first Mickey Mouse cartoon?", "answer": "Plane Crazy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523dfa736d4be723796b49", "question": "What does the \"Calgary Stampede\" bills itself as?", "answer": "The Greatest Outdoor Show on Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e4", "question": "What was the last name of Eddie Murphy\u2019s character in the movie \u201cTrading Places\u201d?", "answer": "Valentine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b4", "question": "What toy was created 20 years before it hit the public shelves?", "answer": "The RC car", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fd", "question": "What is the largest island in the contiguous US states?", "answer": "Long Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beff", "question": "Which snooker player ended Stephen Hendry's five-year unbeaten run at The Crucible?", "answer": "Ken Doherty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a678", "question": "Cincinnati is located on the shores of what river?", "answer": "Ohio River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b73", "question": "Who wrote the play \"Death of a Salesman\"?", "answer": "Arthur Miller", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad2", "question": "Mila Kunis played what role on \"That '70s Show\"?", "answer": "Jackie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b4", "question": "Produced by Francis Ford Coppola, what Academy Award-winning film was released in 1974?", "answer": "The Godfather, Part II", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d6f82596a59cbdfbd3b0", "question": "Who invented the lint roller?", "answer": "Nicholas McKay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9381f6bd93ce3a4e5f67e", "question": "Hippopotomonstrosesquipedaliophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Long words", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e19", "question": "The show \"Ugly Betty\" is based on the telenovela \"Yo soy Betty la fea\" from what Latin American country?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a3b3cf93664eb10486bf", "question": "Who created the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Terry Moore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59bb2a1ac9bff04efae6d75c", "question": "Which UK band had a No. 1 hit in 1965 with their song \"I'm Alive\"?", "answer": "The Hollies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600242004be4723ccac22180", "question": "Which Irish poet, born in 1865, was instrumental in the founding of the Abbey Theatre in Dublin?", "answer": "William Butler Yeats", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b6990cae762b54eb9be9414", "question": "How old was Janet Leigh in her debut film \"The Romance of Rosy Ridge\"?", "answer": "20", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdd4fec223966ae8f8904", "question": "Where was golf's Vijay Singh born?", "answer": "Fiji", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd5f877e98cb97778a35", "question": "In which U.S. state are the Great Sand Dunes located?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e94357ccba3ffe45786d0", "question": "What element is assigned the chemical symbol Cf?", "answer": "Californium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339408", "question": "Who directed the 2003 movie \"Monster\"?", "answer": "Patty Jenkins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a786", "question": "In which US state is Puget Sound located?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b3d7e662d71a53650fe4", "question": "What is the opening section of an opera called?", "answer": "The overture", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bd", "question": "What is measured in Newtons?", "answer": "Force", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887f", "question": "What novel did Ian Fleming introduce James Bond in?", "answer": "Casino Royale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ece", "question": "What sitcom was almost titled \"Six of One\" or \"Across the Hall\"?", "answer": "Friends", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fd", "question": "What do scientists call the \u201cbelt\u201d that is orbiting the sun between Mars and Jupiter?", "answer": "Asteroid Belt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e3f7405cb9e8bda682136e", "question": "What year was the wreck of the Titanic discovered?", "answer": "1985", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0dcd9fcbed638185eaa0d", "question": "The annual \"Christmas Book Flood\" is part of what country\u2019s holiday tradition?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601371ad138175489539638c", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him huge royalties: at the peak of the show's popularity, he took home $800,000 to $900,000 annually.", "category": "entertainment"}]